Currently,
to the best of our knowledge, there is
nothing available in terms of a learning platform
that is catering to the specific learning needs
of somebody with a diagnosis or somebody with
neurodiversity.
This program is targeting specifically people with neurodiversity,
all the topics cater to people with neurodiversity,
all the methodology, cater to people with neurodiversity,
the worksheets,
the training materials, the language, the pace,
the simplicity, the relevance, everything
is catering to this very unique audience.
The mission of this LMS is to meet
neurodiverse learners where they are and teach them
in a style that works for them.
I think what the users will feel is
that here is something that has been simplified,
modified and adapted to the special or the
specific learning needs of somebody with a diagnosis.
As like I said before, there really is
nothing available particularly for this audience.
When I look back, I think the concept
of having an LMS platform or an open
learning platform or a learning management system specifically
for people with neurodiversity came into being with
a always experienced during COVID.
Even before the lockdown was announced in April
2020,
in March itself, we had very consciously
reached a conclusion that there is really nothing
available for this large population of people with
the diagnosis who are now going to be
sitting at home and are going to be
dependent on the schools to open up their
online learning platform for them.
This also came from my own experiences with
my two children who are neuro typical and
they could go online on YouTube and look
at so many activities that they could access
and they could experience and which kept them
occupied and there was nothing really available online
for your cost for our students where they
could even if it was something as simple
as doing an art activity or doing cooking
activity which was catered to their pace, their
speed and their cognitive ability, there was nothing
really available. So I think that what I
value I did for those three months of
lockdown having one free activity on Facebook which
was a live session with so many young
people with neurodiversity and their family participated in.
I think that opened up the whole aspect
of yes, there are neurodiverse people who will
be able to learn from an online platform
as well. So I think the whole inception
or the seed for this learning platform came